MATTEO CRISTIANO

PERSONAL DATA

Residence: Via San Matteo 82G, 00015 Monterotondo (RM)

Mobile phone: +39 349 2913958 E-mail: slb6113@gmail.com

GitHub profile: https://github.com/Sennar19
GitLab profile: https://gitlab.com/slb6113
Twitter profile: https://twitter.com/slb6113

LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/matteo-cristiano-20788a104

Driving license: B, A3 Nationality: Italian

Place and date of birth: Ferrara (Fe), September 10th 1992



EDUCATION

2023 HashiCorp Cloud Engineer Certifications: Terraform Associate 003, released by HashiCorp

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Google IT Support Professional Certificate, released by Coursera

2022 Certificate of Completion of the Architecting on AWS, released by Amazon Web Services (AWS)

2020 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Advanced Networking Specialty (LA) course, released by Linux Academy

2020 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Certified Machine Learning - Speciality course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate Level course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the Learn AWS by Doing course, released by Linux Academy

2019 Certificate of Completion of the Linux Operating System Fundamentals course, released by Linux Academy

2015-2018 **Master's degree** in **Astronomy and Astrophysics**, from "*La Sapienza*" University of Rome, with vote **109/110**, with thesis "*Violent relaxation of self gravitating systems*" (supervisor: Prof. Roberto Capuzzo Dolcetta)

2018 Certificate of Completion of the **Learning Python** course, released by *LinkedIn*

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Parallel I/O and management of large scientific data** course, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *Cineca* offices in Rome

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Introduction to Parallel Computing with MPI and Open MP** course, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *Cineca* offices in Rome

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Debugging and Optimization of Scientific Applications** course, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *Cineca* offices in Rome

2017 Certificate of attendance to **Introduction to Marconi KNL Cluster, for users and developers** workshop, organized during *Cineca HPC Events*, at the *CNR* offices in Rome

2011-2015 Bachelor's degree in Physics and Astrophysics, from "La Sapienza" University of Rome, with vote **106/110**, with thesis "Regolarizzazione del Problema Gravitazionale Classico dei due e tre Corpi" (supervisor: Prof. Roberto Capuzzo Dolcetta)

COMPUTER SKILLS

Linux O.S., Microsoft Windows O.S., Python, Bash Shell Scripting, SQL, Microsoft Visual Studio, AWS, SonarQube, Git, Packer, Ansible, CodePipeline, CodeBuild, RDS, Aurora, API Gateway, Jenkins, Cloud, Terraform, Azure DevOps, Powershell Scripting, Octopus, GSuite, Office 365, Docker, Docker Compose, Kubernetes, ArgoCD, EKS, RedGate, Network, Security, Landing Zone, Documentation, Confluence, Azure, Cloud

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Italian: native language (C2)

French: elementary (A1), both written and spoken English: professional (B2), both written and spoken

WORK EXPERIENCES

June 2023 - present

Cloud Architecture & Operations Expert at Lottomatica, Rome:

I'm working as Cloud Architect, for the Lottomatica Cloud team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on Azure cloud (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, Kubernetes, Graphana, DataBricks, ..), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, and AKS). I'm also involved in the creation of infrastructure, and CI\CD processes of a Data Platform project, managing the MLOps workflow.

April 2022 - June 2023

International Platform Operations Expert at Lottomatica, Rome:

I'm working as Cloud Engineer, for the Lottomatica Cloud team, in an international project: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud (using Terraform), from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Azure DevOps), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes.

I manage creation and integration between different systems (Azure DevOps, ArgoCD, Kubernetes, Graphana, SonarQube, ..), servers life cycle (via Ansible processes), and Kubernetes cluster (on-prem, and EKS). About AWS, I had the possibility to work with Local Zones, and Outposts.

April 2020 - April 2022

System Administrator & Cloud Engineer at ConTe.it - Admiral Group, Rome:

I'm working as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in my role, I manage the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of Cl/CD processes. Recently, I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. I manage the integration between different systems (Graphana, SonarQube, Jenkins, ..), and the servers life cycle via Packer/Ansible processes.

June 2018 - March 2020

<u>Software Developer Junior at ConTe.it - Admiral Group, Rome:</u>

I'm a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework (TDD & BDD methodology, code versioning using Git and CodeCommit); every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process.

ABOUT ME

I'm 31 years old, I'm graduate in "Astronomy and Astrophysic" - at the "La Sapienza" University of Rome - and I'm specialized on dynamics of dense stellar systems and exoplanets systems. I have been for about 2 years a PHP software developer (frontend, and backend), using the Laravel framework; every day, I also used the SQL language (MySQL databases), and managed the static analysis of the code through SonarQube. The projects in which I participated were built on AWS cloud, where I also managed release pipelines (in particular, using CodePipeline, and CodeBuild). In particular, I worked on the migration to AWS (with a serverless architecture, created by myself) of an entire ETL nightly process. I worked as System Administrator and Cloud Engineer, for the ConTe.it Customer team: in this role, I managed the servers and processes built on AWS cloud, from network/security topics to management of release pipelines (in particular, with the use of Jenkins), up to the creation/management of CI/CD processes. I also assumed the role of administrator of the company's WordPress applications. At the moment, I'm working as Cloud Architecture & Operations Expert, at Lottomatica, managing VMs, kubernetes clusters, and CI\CD processes built on AWS and Azure clouds. I am also interested in Machine Learning and Data Science topics/processes. I'm an extrovert guy, I like to work in team (more brains are better than one!), and I'm always ready to test and improve my own skills, overcoming my limits.

Ctrl - Create the roaring impossible

Monterotondo (RM), 01/02/2024

Matteo Cristiano